Patrick Larson

Software Engineer

github.com/patrickslarson8 • linkedin.com/in/patrick-larson8

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with seven years of experience in military service, including one year of experience developing and deploying mission-critical software solutions. I have an additional two years of experience coding for personal projects. My career made me a driven problem solver with excellent communication, collaboration, and customer service skills. My education focuses on hard engineering including electrical engineering, network management and security, and most recently artificial intelligence.

SELECTED ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Al Project using computer vision to autonomously plug in an electric vehicle
 - Skills Leveraged: Python | TensorFlow | Computer Vision | Linux OS
- Developed and maintained database application to track the progress of students through Army Aviation flight school, revolutionizing the administrative workflow
 - Skills Leveraged: SQL | Visual Basic | MS Access
- Airport Check-in Queuing Simulation to study the principles of Object-Oriented Programming
 - Skills Leveraged: C++ | OOP
- Desktop application project to manage classes, students, and teachers of an organization to learn the fundamentals of C#
 - Skills Leveraged: C# | SQL | OOP

CERTIFICATIONS

- TensorFlow Developer (ID: 56236042)
- Azure Data Science Associate (ID: 994164510)

EXPERIENCE

Oct 2022 – Present MICROSOFT – SOFTWARE AND SYSTEMS ACADEMY

REMOTE

- Competitive and rigorous computer science fundamentals program
- Created and debugged over 20 console and desktop applications
- Training in skills including C#, T-SQL, Algorithms, Data Structures, OOP, HTML5, ASP.Net, and Git

Oct 2021 – Oct 2022 U.S. ARMY – SENIOR INSTRUCTOR

FORT RUCKER, AL

- Restructured organization improving instructor expertise and effectiveness
- Streamlined outdated workflows by developing SharePoint sites and student tracking database

Jan 2020 – Oct 2021 U.S. ARMY – DOCTRINE INSTRUCTOR

FORT RUCKER, AL

- Trained and mentored over 700 students in my tenure
- Certified in Army Equal Opportunity and Resilience programs

JAN 2017 – JAN 2020 U.S. ARMY – HELICOPTER PLATOON LEADER

FORT HOOD, TX

- Routinely deployed and maintained networks of computers in mission-critical roles, reducing planning and mission response times
- Leveraged analytics software to exceed operational maintenance standards by 10%
- Organized the daily operations and reporting of 40 personnel and flight operations including 350 flights and 1,400 flight hours with impeccable service to requesting units

MAY 2015 – JAN 2017 U.S. ARMY – HELICOPTER FLIGHT SCHOOL

FORT RUCKER, AL

Trained and certified in the Boeing CH-47F cargo helicopter

EDUCATION

Jan 2022 – Present Whiting School of Engineering at Johns Hopkins University

Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence

BALTIMORE, MD

- Anticipated completion Summer 2024
- 4.0 in related coursework

Jul 2011 – May 2015 UNITED STATES MILITARY ACADEMY

WEST POINT, NY

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

• Focus on computer hardware and networking fundamentals

• Competed in an inaugural NSA-sponsored network security competition